Now we're covering monitor and control the
project work ITTOs.
So we are now moving into the monitoring
and controlling process group.
Please look at your process map for that.
With every one of them, we are reviewing
tracking against the plan.
All right, we are in integration.
This is what we, the PMs, focus on because
we are managing, coordinating every aspect
of that project all right so everything
happening below rolls up to us in
integration so just keep that in mind so
here you will track progress of the
project so you should be on page one zero
five in your pinback so the inputs of
course your project management plan comes
in it will contain all the components plus
the baselines Remember scope, time,
and cost.
Our project documents will come in.
You can't memorize all these, so I don't
need to cover each of these here.
Big, big, big will be work performance
information.
So I know this is covered in another
section, but we talked about data when we
were directing and managing the project
work.
Everything happening below, because we
were in executing, everything happened.
below rolls up to us we put all that data
together those were your actuals raw
observations and measurements well each of
the controlling processes below us
remember we're up in integration each of
the monitoring and controlling processes
below us will compare the plan so that
always comes in your project management
plan to the data what's
actually happening the
plan includes the baselines
what was approved.
We're comparing it to the data,
what's actually happening in executing.
All right, we're trying to look for
variance.
So you're going to see that
every monitoring and controlling
process below us creates
work performance information.
That is the progress.
Progress, if you look at your process map,
progress of validating scope, progress
with controlling scope,
progress with controlling the
schedule, progress with
controlling our costs, etc.
Every single monitoring and controlling
process below us will create information.
All that will feed up to us.
We're going to put all that progress
called information together to create work
performance reports that will go out to
our stakeholders.
So that's where work performance.
information comes from all the monitoring
and controlling processes below progress
so we up at the top in integration are
comparing our plan what was agreed upon to
the information the total progress what
else comes in agreements because we do
have to make sure we're meeting
contractual obligations and then you have
those EEFs and OPAs
so tools and techniques
will use expert judgment
We'll do data analysis.
So the big thing we're looking for here is
variance.
Are we off from our plan baselines so that
we can quickly take action?
We're looking for variance as are every
monitoring and controlling
process below us.
Doing so, we will then look for alternatives
if things aren't going quite right.
What are different alternative ways of
doing things?
do a cost benefit analysis.
The benefit should always outweigh the
costs, of course.
And we will also do earn
value analysis that will
be covered in detail when
we're controlling costs.
So you'll see when controlling schedule
and costs are done together.
We're actually monitoring
and controlling every bit, but
that's where we will actually
calculate earned value.
All right, we will also do root cause
analysis.
If something is wrong, we need to find out
what actually caused it.
So you'll see later, cause and effect
diagrams are used, aka Ishikawa,
fish phone diagrams.
We need to uncover what's causing a problem
so we can implement preventive action.
We'll make decisions.
It's not always just us, of course.
So we are team members can vote.
And of course, we, we're having a meeting
to review every aspect of the project.
So big, big, big,
information progress came
in from all the controlling
processes below.
We put all that information progress
together to create work performance reports.
That contains everything that's happening
with our project.
It's and reports will be sent out to
stakeholders.
Whoever wants to know what's happening
with every aspect of the project.
It's with work performance reports.
We raise awareness, take action,
and can make decisions only with the work
performance reports, knowing what's
happening with every aspect of the project.
Things aren't progressing as planned.
Change requests.
Still has to go to perform integrated
change control, but if the change request
is approved, we update any plans that
include baselines and documents accordingly.
That's a trio every time.